tethertools.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy & Security – Tether Tools

This policy was last updated on May 18, 2018.

## Who we are

Our website addresses are: https://www.tethertools.com, https://www.tethertalk.com, and http://www.tethertools.eu.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact and Web Forms

Information submitted on any Tether Tools web forms will be collected and stored. This information will not be shared with anyone other than Tether Tools staff unless explicitly noted on the web form the information was collected on.

### Cookies

When you visit our site, we may ask your browser to place a permanent “cookie” (a very small text file) on your computer. If your browser is configured to accept cookies, it will accept the cookie and place it on your computer’s hard drive. We collect this information to analyze where our customers are coming from and how often they visit our site. We also collect certain technical information from your computer, like your IP address and the address of a referring web site, if any. This information will allow us to enhance our site to our customer’s preferences. This information is used only for the benefit of Tether Tools and you, our customer.

You can visit our site without cookies if you choose to do so. However, please be aware that some features of the site may not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies. To visit our site without cookies, you can configure your browser to reject all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is set. Check the browsers help menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

If you place an order with a ship-to address that differs from your bill-to address, we retain this information. You can modify or correct this information by following the procedure described above. Such information is used at your request to ship purchased merchandise and may also be used for marketing purposes, but will not be sold to any third parties.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select "Remember Me", your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Google AdWords (Advertising Cookies)  

Our website uses [Google AdWords](https://adwords.google.com/) Conversion Tracking cookie to measure and optimize the performance and user experience related to our ads in Google Search or selected Google Display Network sites. Learn more about Google’s privacy policy here. 

Opt-out: Visiting [Google’s Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

Google Analytics (Functional Cookies)

Our website uses [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/), a web analysis service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). Learn more from their [Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). 

### Placing an Order

When you decide to place an order, you are asked to complete an order form. The order form requires your name, billing and shipping address, credit card number, expiration date and CID#. You should also include other information fields such as your telephone number, to allow us to contact you regarding your order if necessary. This information is collected to make your shopping experience with us as smooth and pleasant as possible. It is used only for the benefit of Tether Tools and you, our customer.

Credit card information is not stored by Tether Tools

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who we share your data with

We do not sell our users’ or customers’ personal information.

We do not share your data with any other entity unless expressly noted at the time of collection. 

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

For users that fill out website forms, we store that information indefinitely as a record of the event.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Credit card information is securely sent to PayPal for authorization and collection. It is not stored on Tether Tools servers.

## Your contact information

You can contact us at any time to: 

  * Request access to information that Tether Tools has about you
  * Correct any information that Tether Tools has about you
  * Delete information that Tether Tools has about you

If you have any additional questions about Tether Tools collection and storage of data, please contact us at:  
Tether Tools  
2202 E. McDowell Rd.  
Suite 5  
Phoenix, AZ 85050

+1 480-284-4114  
privacy@tethertools.com 

## Additional information

### Security

The security of your personal information is very important to us. In an effort to protect your personal information, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology with 128 bit encryption. If your browser supports SSL (most current browsers do), it will automatically encrypt the information you provide to us on the secure pages on our site, before sending it over the Internet.

Tether Tools has obtained a digital certificate from Go Daddy, a leading provider of Internet trust services.

To authenticate the security of your connection before submitting any of your personal information, you can double click on the icon to display our digital certificate.

### How we protect your data

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our websites for potential vulnerabilities and attacks. 

### What third parties we receive data from

Tether Tools will sometimes receive contact information from Tether Tools partners. This is typically when a user enters a third party promotion, contest, or giveaway in which Tether Tools has partnered. We make every effort to make sure the third-party has notified users of this share and the submission of that data would fall under the third-party’s privacy policy.

Once Tether Tools receives that data, the management, storage and usage of that data falls under this privacy policy

### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

Tether Tools may use user data to GEO locate customers for determining shipping charges and sending targeted emails. Additionally, we may use elements of user data to customize the website experience presenting information, photos and content more relevant to the end user.
